# KORFY WITHAM

East Barre, VT 05461 | ikoreyvt@gmail.com | 802.522.9804

### FULL STACK SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

After 8 years in freight operations, I am excited to pursue a new career in software development. I appreciate being challenged at work and have found some interesting similarities between operations and coding including problem-solving and identifying trends and patterns. One of the key differences, and something I'm really enjoying, is that coding produces tangible results – I love the feeling of building things with my own hands. When not coding I enjoy riding my bike, playing video games, and cooking – and always with music on.

## **TECHNICAL SKILLS SUMMARY**

Languages Frameworks Version Control Development CSS | HTML | JavaScript MongoDB | React | Node.js Git | GitHub Visual Studio | Notepad++

### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Capstone Company TBD

VT

Jul 2021 - Aug 2021

**Developer – Capstone Project, Burlington Code Academy** 

Will be a member of a 4-person team – project specifics TBD.

#### TForce Freight (formerly UPS Freight)

**Burlington, VT** 

Sep 2019 – May 2021

International LTL/Truckload company owned by Canadian company TFI International.

#### **Outbound (Operations) Supervisor**

Led the PM shift with primary responsibility for outbound p.m. operations and logistics including loading and unloading, dynamic lane decisions, pickups and deliveries, driver schedules and safety, damages, etc. A significant amount of time was spent on customer service, communicating directly with customers regarding their unique needs and handling unexpected challenges.

Led a team of ~15 workers; continuously met and/or exceeded daily and quarterly benchmarks

FedEx Freight Berlin, VT Nov 2013 – Jun 2019

The business unit of the FedEx enterprise handling LTL and Truckload services both nationwide and internationally.

Team Lead (Outbound Supervisor)

Feb 2018 - Jun 2019

Freight Handler, Quality Coach, Driver Apprentice

Nov 2013 - Feb 2018

Held several roles over the years – started out as a <u>Freight Handler</u> right out of high school and quickly became one of the best workers on a forklift. Took on the responsibility of <u>Quality Coach</u> tasked with recuperating damaged freight and ensuring bay freight was loaded for maximum efficiency. As a <u>Driver Apprentice</u>, obtained a CDL permit and required endorsements while working on the dock. As <u>Team Lead</u>, in addition to handling freight, took over customer service communication and dispatch board assignments.

Other Jobs	VT	<u> 2006 – 2013 &amp; 2016 – 2018</u>
C.P. Dudley Store, East Montpelier, VT	Deli Worker	2016 – 2018
Champlain Valley Mobile Care, Richmond, VT	Carpenter's Assistant	PT/Seasonal 2006 – 2013

# Education / Certification

Full Stack Web Developer (480+ hours) Software Engineering Coursework

Burlington Code Academy Vermont Technical College (expected) Aug 2021

2014 - 2015